[music]
[Instructor] Cool, so we've got a lot
of awesome functionality in our game now,
so you can see the Player jumping
because they're so excited,
and you see all of these Obstacles
moving through the Scene.
Now, the one thing that you notice
is that the Player is
standing incredibly still.
Now, that's either
because of one of two reasons.
Either the Player is moving
so slow
that they're not actually moving
at all,
or the Player's moving so fast
that our eyes can't even perceive
how fast the Player's moving,
and so we can only see
it as standing still.
I'll leave
that up to your own interpretation.
So in order to actually make
the Player
look like they're moving
in this Scene
that's constantly moving
back and forth,
we're going to need
to Play with
the Player's animation.
So what we're going to do is,
we're actually going
to click on the Player,
and then in their Inspector,
you can see that there's actually
an Animator
Component already applied to it,
and it has a Controller
for a SimpleCharacter,
so what we can do is
we can actually...
double-click on that
SimpleCharacter box,
and now you see that it actually
opens up
a brand new window
in our Scene for Animators.
Now, if you want to see all
of the different windows
that you could actually add to Unity,
you can actually see on the top-left
there's the "Window" button,
and then you can actually add a bunch
of other windows that you can use.
One that you might've seen before;
actually, our console
is where the game over message
is being sent.
So you can add other windows
if you want to.
So now, in our Animator window,
you can see that we have a strange view
of this button
that says entry but not
really anything else.
You can actually move around in
this view, there's a lot more going on,
so we can press the Alt key,
and hold it,
and then left-click,
and drag, and we can move around
our little Animator window here,
or we can use our mouse wheel,
and scroll in and out
to zoom in and out, and if you click
on your mouse wheel,
and hold,
and then you drag it around,
you can actually move
around that way.
So there's a lot of different
things happening
in our little
Animator window here.
Now first and foremost,
the Animator Controller
is the way that we
actually control the states
that the character is
in at the current moment.
So, in fact,
when we're pressing Play,
our Animator Controller goes
straight to our "Idle" animation,
which is why it looks
like the Player is not moving at all.
The Player's not moving,
surprise.
They're not moving incredibly fast,
they're just not moving at all.
So our Animator Controller
actually controls
all of the different states
that our character can be in,
so our character can be idle,
and then from idle,
these arrows actually mean
that they then can go into one
of these different states.
So, it can go from idle
into a "Walk_Static" state,
which means
that they're not actually walking
in a direction,
they're just walking in place.
You can also run in place
with "Run_Static".
You can walk in a direction
using "Walk",
or you can "Run" in a direction.
And so, if you started to move,
for example,
maybe it'll go to the Walk animation,
and then when you stop moving,
it'll go back to your Idle animation
so you stand still.
Now, a really cool thing is
you can actually see
what these different animations
are like,
so if we zoom in a little bit,
if we were to double-click on Idle,
you can actually see that it pops
up a little animation preview,
and we can actually press Play,
and you can see that the Model
isn't actually really doing
anything.
You can see it's just kind of waving
its arms back and forth.
If we choose, for example,
Walk_Static,
double-click on that,
we have another animation,
and so you can see
it actually looks
like this character's
walking, which is cool.
If we double-click on run,
and we press Play,
you can see that this one is
actually moving
through the Scene, compared
to if we go to...
run static,
this one runs in place,
so very helpful
to know the states
of all of these things.
If we take a look at the arrows,
you can actually see...
all of the different conditions
that need to happen
to actually make the character move,
which we'll go into a little bit
on how we can edit those and see those.
So you can see we have these conditions
for an actual speed, so say
the Player is not moving,
their speed is 0,
and then they start moving,
and it reaches a point where it's .25,
then it will actually go
into this transition,
and you can see this transition happen.
So, they're stopped,
and then they start moving,
and then it goes into walk static,
and the Player is just moving.
So, now what you're going to do is,
you're going to left-click
on the Player in the Hierarchy,
and then under the Inspector
in the Animator Component,
where you see Controller,
you're going to double-click
on SimpleCharacter.
This will open
up your Animator window
for your Player character,
and so now,
you can go look around, and see
all of the different animation states,
you can click into...
the different states
by double-clicking on them,
and then you can preview their different
animations like walking static
or walking,
and then you can take a look
at some of the different transitions,
and see the different conditions
that they need to follow
to be able to move.
Now it's your turn.
[music]